Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to create some spikes.
If our player character overlaps these spikes, we're going to make them become damaged.
To get started, let's go over to the item folder and go over to the item image folder.
Then briefly close on our engine and attached In this lecture, I'm going to make sure to include these
images of some spikes.
Drag them into your Unreal project.
Then if we go over to our items folder, just right click on the checkpoint blueprint and duplicate
it and just cool this off.
Spikes underscore BP.
And if we open it up.
Go over to the viewport and select the paper flipbook.
We can just delete this and instead go ad and look for Sprite.
And on the sauce.
Right.
Select the spikes that we just imported.
Okay.
I think these are a good size.
Just make the box condition that around these spikes.
Then select us bright and just scroll down and make sure it has its collision.
AS No collision.
As by default, sprites will block everything.
We can just delete this checkpoint location as we don't need it.
Then if we go back to our event graph and just delete this set checkpoint and set up book and instead,
if our player character overlaps these works, we're going to just drag off them and look for apply
damage and we're going to apply one damage if our player character overlaps a spike and for the damage
causer, just drag up and look for self and then go compile.
So we can test this out.
I'm going to drag in my spike somewhere in my world.
Put them in their 20.
And if I could play.
If I walk into these bikes, I become damaged.
I kind of smell.
So let's make them a bit bigger.
So I'm going to select my pepper spray and I'll make it like four.
Lastly, let me get 2.5 and I'll just adjust my box.
Okay, so that looks a bit better.
So there are some spikes.
I go into them, I become damaged.
One more thing with your spikes.
Maybe you want it so that the enemies can actually be damaged by our spikes.
If that's the case, you can go over to your spikes.
And instead of just casting to the player character, we can just delete this and just drag other actor
and hook us up here.
So I actually think I'll do that if we go compile and save this.
If my enemy walks into the spike, it should now become damaged.
So if I go play and my enemy walks into it, it becomes damaged.
So maybe you want that, maybe you don't.
But for now, we can leave this as it kind of makes our game a bit more dynamic so I can hit my enemy
into a spike and then it will do like two damage.